[Music]
exercise recommendations for obesity
have been referred to as the mysterious
case of a public health guideline that
is almost entirely ignored governmental
scientific and professional
organizations call for at least an hour
of exercise a day for weight management
but almost no obese adults meet this
target a survey suggests American men
and women watch TV 10 times more than
they exercise and for obese Americans it
may be even worse just two% even reach
30 minutes a day and the percentage
exceeding an hour a day is expected to
be close to zero why don't obese
individuals exercise more how about we
just ask them when questioned obese
adults typically describe exercise as
being unpleasant uncomfortable and
unenjoyable how can we break this
vicious cycle where inactivity can lead
to weight gain which can lead to further
inactivity and even more weight gain uh
the first thing to recognize is that it
is normal and natural to be physically
lazy right nothing in biology makes
sense except in the light of evolution
the title of a famous essay written by a
noted geneticist laziness is in our
genes we evolved to instinctually avoid
unnecessary exertion to conserve energy
for survival and reproduction uh these
days there's no shortage of available
fuel yet the hardwired inertia remains
our ancient ancestors exercised only
when it was necessary or when it was fun
as a form of Play Just Like dietary
change for weight control the only way
exercise is going to work long term is
if it becomes a stable lifelong habit
exercise is really only effective if
it's sustainable so we need to
restructure our surroundings to require
more physical activity like using a
treadmill desk and figure out how to
make exercise more enjoyable it should
just be like a you know walk in the park
literally perhaps wise advice from a
1925 medical journal entry the best
prescription to be written for a walk is
to take a dog and a friend listening to
your favorite music might also help
music has been described as a legal
method for improving Peak Performance
and warm importantly the enjoyment of
high-intensity interval training during
exercise listening to a preferred
playlist can significantly reduce your
rate of perceived exertion which is how
hard you feel your body is working right
put severely obese youth on a treadmill
and have them go until exhaustion with
or without music and those listening to
their favorite Tunes tended to make it
about 5% longer uh this was chalked up
to attentional distraction the music may
have just helped them keep their mind
off of the feeling feelings of fatigue I
mean if that's the case maybe you know
listen to a podcast or Audi book might
have a similar Effect one way to up your
walking game is with walking poles
so-called Nordic walking also known as
exer striding or Viking hiking was
originally developed in Scandinavia to
maintain a cross-country ski Athletes
Training in the summer but it's since
gained in popularity worldwide is a
general fitness activity the augmented
engagement of the upper body musculature
may result in a 18 to 22% increased
calorie expenditure over walking alone
depending in part on your pole handling
technique uh the question I wanted to
know for my new book though was does
that actually translate into accelerated
weight loss before and after studies
demonstrate weight loss with pull
walking compared to a sedentary control
what about compared to regular walking
of the four such studies I could locate
comparing Thrice weekly 40 to 60 Minute
sessions of Nordic walking compared to
regular walking every single one found
no significant difference in body fat
measures after eight weeks 12 weeks 12
weeks or 13 weeks uh there are certainly
other benefits over regular walking such
as increased upper body muscle bulk
muscular endurance and strength right
though not as much as resistance band
training uh but to date there's no
evidence for a weight loss enhancing
effect which is why Nordic walking
didn't make the cut for my new book but
just as we were going to press this
study was published the first ever to
combine Nordic walking with diet
compared to the same dietary program
with regular walking and once again no
significant difference in body weight or
anything else H now there was a hint
that those in the poll group enjoyed it
more and in the end right exercise only
works if you do it and there may be
other benefits Nordic walking beat out
regular walking in terms of reducing
symptoms of depression and improving
Sleep Quality uh perhaps this should not
be surprising given the greater exercise
intensity of Nordic walking even
approaching that of jogging at higher
speeds and that's where I see the role
of walking poles to to fill the kind of
intensity gap between people who are
ready to graduate from walking but not
yet ready for more rigorous activities
such as running the only potential
downsides are the added expense and
reminded of Monty Python's Ministry of
silly walks sketch the the indignity of
looking a bit
[Music]
ridiculous